[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
I'm wasting my damned time.
I'm trying to open this elevator, but I'm
90% sure this elevator only goes down,
like everything else here.
That's pretty far down, though.
All this security must be
protect something.
I bet we have gnomes down there
mining precious metals and gems.
I want a gnome.
Damn, there's another alien.
I'd put my gnome in a cage and feed
him granola.  I think they'd eat that.
Eh, who am I kidding?
If the aliens got down there, they'd
have eaten them all by now anyway.
Gnomes are small.
Wait, are gnomes even real?
[headcrab squeals]
I can't re--WHOA!
Dammit, I'm being followed again.
What happened to that soldier guy?
I thought he was taking care of this?
Nobody's doing their job.
Why is everyone who's
not me such a problem?
Y'know, some people might argue
I'm only focusing on the negative,
but I think that's because I
can't think of one thing today
anyone else has done right.
All anyone has been doing today
has been breaking things,
running around screaming,
shooting the wrong people,
or dying.
I mean, what am I
supposed to say to people?
"Wow, you sure did a good job
falling down that elevator shaft!"
Or "Way to lock yourself inside
the freezer.  I'm so proud of you."
Hey, this is the homeless guy's foundation.
I'm going in circles again!
I'd better speed up.
If going to go in circles,
I want to go faster.
Wait, wait wait, wait, wait.
I haven't checked this tunnel out, and
I'm still waiting for hidden treasure.
We get funding for
a lot of shady projects.
Maybe there's some Nazi gold back here.
Siegen sie mir das geld.
Eh, there's nothing here.
Just a dead end and some more boxes.
Probably filled with
network cards we can't use.
BNC or something.
Well, back on the labyrinth ride.
See, I'm remaining calm
about going in circles
because I know I haven't investigated
every possible path yet.
See, there's one.
I don't know where that goes.
Some people stay lost their
WHOLE LIVES!
Eeeh...
In fact, most people.
EVERYONE!
Everyone's lost, except me.
Except for right now.
There's that hook again.
I'm going to come back here
if I can't find the right way.
I won't be surprised if this entire track
is devoted to taking people in circles,
but I will be disappointed.
Hey, there's one of those signs
again that might do something.
I'm going to shoot it.
That's so weird; it spins the wrong way.
Now, did that actually do anything, or am
I shooting at things for no reason again?
Ah!  It did!
I'm surprised that worked.
I wouldn't have thought that shooting
road signs was the correct thing to do.
[rumbling]
I always thought that--
Jesus Christ, are we running a
geothermal plant down here, too?
Stop, stop.
Okay, a dead body and an
alien who hasn't seen me yet.
I can put one and one together.
Actually, that's one and negative one.
Now it's negative two and me.
But wait, wouldn't I be number one?
I don't know what
the hell I'm talking about.
See, this is why you
have to define your terms.
If you don't, people die.
Oop, there's that tentacle again.
Bad spot, chunky.
Get it all up, I'll wait.
I should've just driven the tram
straight through it, but, I dunno,
that might've caused it to come
crashing down on top of me.
Wouldn't want that.
I wonder if circus people
already know about these things.
Carnies.
Some of the strangest things I've ever seen
in my life have been at the freak show.
Ah, but they had the freaks in
cages where they belong!
Back.  There might be something here.
Besides death, I mean.
I doubt there will be.
I'm sure I'll go up the stairs and
find nothing but a stack of dead bodies,
with a smiley-faced sticker attached--
[headcrab squeals]
Fugh!
That was sneaky!
Where did you go?!
Well, let that be a lesson to you.
How did those bastards know to jump towards
the only vulnerable part of my body?
If I was quick enough, I might be able
to headbutt them, but I don't--
Now, what's this?  The sentry gun?
It can't be bothered to shoot
those aliens crawling around,
yet it has no problems
seeing me through a wall?
These things cause more
problems than they solve.
Ah-hah!  Buttons!
What did that do?
Oh, it moved the hook.
So, why the hell was
that there in the first place?
Well, that opens up some options.
And I'm going to be Mr. Efficiency
and switch the track while I'm up here.
Because maybe I'm just a pessimist,
but I get the sneaking sensation
this track is going to find a way
to send me back in circles again.
I mean, why should it be any different
than anything else in this building?
I don't think this tram
has any real function here.
It's just some CEO's fantasy track.
Why have a model train
that goes in circles
when you can afford the real thing?
Aah!
Yeah, I'm sure before long, I'll start
seeing some giant Styrofoam trees.
I will say that I do dig this
sign-shooting track switch system.
I mean, I thought there'd be a
control station with--Ah, wire!
I AM going in circles.
But no, they just want
you to shoot the signs.
Like drunk hillbillies shooting
deer-crossing signs from their pickups.
Works for me.
[imitating banjo plucking]
[machine gun fire]
Hm.  Gunfire.
I've changed my stance
from that being a happy thing.
HEY, DON'T MIND ME, GUYS!
I'M JUST PASSING THROUGH!
OKAY! YOU CAN CUT THAT OUT!
I'M REALLY NOT TRYING
TO GET IN ANYBODY'S WAY!
OH MY GOD!  WHY IS EVERYONE SO HOSTILE?!
THIS THING'S SPINNING!
I'M GETTING DIZZY!
I CAN'T SHOOT YOU
ACCURATELY WHEN I'M DIZZY!
WHERE ARE YOU?!
NO!
YOU FLANKING ME?
I'M...READY...SORT OF!
[exhales]
I think I'm just going to
take a breather for a minute.
I should've been a pirate.